<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel> <title>Practicalli Personal Journal</title><description>Daily journal of thoughts and experiences</description><link>https://practical.li/journal/</link><atom:link href="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /> <managingEditor>Practicalli</managingEditor><docs>https://github.com/practicalli/journal/</docs><language>en</language> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 23:51:05 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 23:51:05 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.17.9</generator> <image> <url>https://github.com/practicalli/graphic-design/blob/live/logos/practicalli-logo.png?raw=true</url> <title>Practicalli Personal Journal</title> <link>https://practical.li/journal/</link> </image> <item> <title>Bikes Assembled, Clojure updated</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>neovim</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>tui</category> <category>zensical</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#clojure&#34;&gt;Clojure Monthy updates&lt;/a&gt; for the CLI aliases and Project Templates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Neovim&#34;&gt;Neovim update of plugins&lt;/a&gt; for the Practicalli Astro5 configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Compilation and install of &lt;a href=&#34;#tui-apps&#34;&gt;a TUI app to play music from YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, which has an excellent selection of music available. I prefer using the TUI to the YouTube Music website.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A quick trip to the Coney Hall cycle shop fixed a troublesome hub in the rear wheel, checked with the mechanic on how to assemble the compression plug, donation of an old rear wheel, and collection of a 100mm and 110mm stem to test out the correct length for a good bike fit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My rim brake wheels are starting to wear out, after 20 years of riding. I will seek out some Fulcrum wheels so I can keep the original look. Fulcrum Racing 5, 3, 1 or zero wheels are options. The Racing Zero wheels are the lightest at around 1430 grams, as they use aluminium bladed spokes. Probably nicer than some of the cheaper carbon wheels.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A review of my tennis elbow and trigger finger with the local GP. I am being referred to advanced Physiotherapy to see if I need an injection in my finger to relieve the locking. From the x-ray of my hand there was no sign of Osteoarthritis (yet) although my blood test did indicate markers for rheumatoid arthritis.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/bikes-assembled-clojure-updated/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 23:44:50 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/bikes-assembled-clojure-updated/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/bikes-assembled-clojure-updated.png" type="image/png" length="53615" /> </item> <item> <title>Long cold winter</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>github</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The week started very cold but there is hope for a slightly warmer day on Wednesday. This is probably the last nice day for a ride this month. With the weather forcasts all taling about an unstable Polar Vortex, the next couple of weeks may not be that great for cycling out doors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I will be planning a bicycle trip around the Loch Lomond area in early spring. I have a friend who lives near by so it will be great to catch up with them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As part of my digital storage and services clean-up I found a fairly simple way to &lt;a href=&#34;#github&#34;&gt;show which GitHub repositories I had stared&lt;/a&gt;, which are probably quite numerous over the last decade or more and of varying relevance.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This week I have been listening to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nessa_Barrett&#34;&gt;Nessa Barrett&lt;/a&gt; who is the single &#34;Dying on the inside&#34;, which I can emathise with to some extent (different situations, similar feelings).&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/long-cold-winter/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 22:51:43 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/long-cold-winter/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/long-cold-winter.png" type="image/png" length="42658" /> </item> <item> <title>Hoping for a stable polar vortex</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Its mostly raining so I am taking the opportunity to go through all my files and notes from the last decade. Reviwing which info is still useful, what needs refreshing and what can go to the digital heaven 🙂&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I got out for two cycle rides this week, Tuesday for a ride to Melia&#39;s Cafe and Saturday Club ride.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Saturday afternoon I helped with my neighbours plumbing. The boiler was banging, so I topped up the hot water tank from the mains. The heating failed to come that morning, so I also reset the boiler and used the manual switch to send hot water to the boiler. That evening the hot water was going to the radiators according to the set schedule.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/hoping-for-a-stable-polar-vortex/</link> <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:51:45 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/hoping-for-a-stable-polar-vortex/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/hoping-for-a-stable-polar-vortex.png" type="image/png" length="52752" /> </item> <item> <title>Just warm enough to cycle</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I am doing a big cycling challenge in Summer so January is the month to check I can still ride my bike and everything on the bike is running smoothly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The number of days with nice weather for cycling may be few and far between this month. Ideally the weather should be above 5 Celcius and dry conditions, especially for cycling around the Kent countryside.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have been doing some post holidays shopping on line, mostly winter kit and improvements to the bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/just-warm-enough-to-cycle/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 22:19:21 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/just-warm-enough-to-cycle/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/just-warm-enough-to-cycle.png" type="image/png" length="49510" /> </item> <item> <title>Happy new year</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Kingdom is feeling the force of the arctic thats to high pressure subsuming the gulf stream. This week will be very cold with ice around on roads and paths.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walking will continue to be the main exercise until the weather is more conducive to cycling.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Started planning for the Dragon Ride event in summer. I&#39;ve ordered new jockey wheels to make the chain run very smooth, a smaller saddle bag, a lighter light and some cycling kit to keep me warm on colder rides.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/happy-new-year/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 21:13:12 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/happy-new-year/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/happy-new-year.png" type="image/png" length="41431" /> </item> <item> <title>End of a good year, start of an even better one</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>debian</category> <category>neovim</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The last week of 2025 and the start of 2026.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Started 2026 with a Park Run (jog) with a Strava time of 27 minutes 46 seconds, but that doesn&#39;t seem right as I think my fitness tracker got confused. My Park Run recorded time was 35 minutes and 25 seconds, which isn&#39;t bad considering I was a minute late to the start :rolling_on_the_floor_laughing:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My injuries continue to recover. I have some exercises to help with &#39;tennis elbow&#39; and &#39;trigger finger&#39; in my left arm and hand. An icy walk to the Podiatrist on Friday confirms that the diabetic ulcer has pretty much gone, so now I can start testing activities to see if any of them stop the ulcer from completely healing or getting worse.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Started the slow migration from Material for MkDocs to Zensical. The first step is to create a new book with Zensical before migrating existing books. I&#39;ve started by creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://practical.li/cycling&#34;&gt;Practicalli Cycling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Preparing for a lot of cycling in the new year with some shopping for bicycle and general winter items.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Shimano R8000 Cassette, 11-32&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Shimano HG701 Chain&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Cospo Cadence sensor (the Garmin sensor got lost some where)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Insulated stainless steel water bottles - stop my water getting even colder during the winter months&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;neck warmers, with breathable mesh around mouth (stop the warmer getting too damp)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;mini bike chain pliers - small enough to carry in top bag in case of issues with chain&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;XOSS XL400 light - a lighter weight light for shorter rides (up to 4 hours)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;mini cycle saddle bag - a compact bag for TPU inner tubes which should not obstruct the rear light mounted on the seat post&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Testing out the reliability of the NAS raid array by watching some classic movies via the DNLP server.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/end-of-a-good-year-start-of-an-even-better-one/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:14:59 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/end-of-a-good-year-start-of-an-even-better-one/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/end-of-a-good-year-start-of-an-even-better-one.png" type="image/png" length="57245" /> </item> <item> <title>Pagan festival parties</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>nas</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The winter holiday season is usually a quiet affair for me as friends and family are dispersed all over the planet. I do not follow a religion although I do appreciate the sun rising every day. I have cats to keep me company and I also look after my neighbours cat for a few days.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Winter is when I do less cycling outside, especially when there is a risk of ice. Instead I work on my core muscles with yoga and occasional brave the outside for a Park Run. I have had an injury on my foot which has taken a few months to heal (as I have been very active), so Park Run events for me will be a brisk part walk (maybe running for the last 50 meters).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Started to consider what this year has meant for me by looking at other peoples 2025 round-ups. The most enjoyable roundup so far is &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/qdI2e8fmx40?si=-Ln3I1uJ41S4lN72&#34;&gt;Kermod &amp;amp; Mayo&#39;s Best and Worst Films of the Year&lt;/a&gt;, which also included best TV shows (that Mark Kermod has watched) of the year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have a Network Attached Storage (NAS) device at home as a convenient central backup for work and media files. The NAS was configured with a RAID6 array, but unfortunately two disks in the RAID 6 array had failed. I discovered that changing 2 disks on the RAID array was not necessarily a safe option, especially if yet another disk became faulty during the rebuild (which can take many hours).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am attempting again to recover the RAID array. If that fails, I will rebuild the NAS with 2 separate RAID6 arrays, increasing further the resilience of the storage in case of hardware issues.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Eventually I will replace the &#39;disk&#39; drives with solid state storage devices (SSD), especially as a 4TB SSD can be found for around 160 GBP. Using SSD rather than spinning &#39;disks&#39; also makes the NAS device really quite.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;NOTE: I have other backup mechanisms as RAID should not be used as a permanent backup solution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Entertainment this week included&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Blakes 7 season 3 (usually watched as I fall asleep)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Slow Horses season 5 - excellent show that keeps my gripped (watched the first 4 episodes in one night)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Pol1bus - wonderfully funny and quirky show (I am not sure if I am rooting for the right protagonists)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Foundation season 1 &amp;amp; 2 - watched again in preparation for season 3 this week&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Dr Who - watching Jodie Whittaker as the Thirteenth doctor and really enjoying the depth of stories that are portrait&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/pagan-festival-parties/</link> <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:26:53 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/pagan-festival-parties/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/pagan-festival-parties.png" type="image/png" length="48858" /> </item> <item> <title>Continuing to downsize</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>practicalli</category> <category>recycle</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;As its coming up to the festive season, I though it would be a great time to &lt;a href=&#34;#donating-tech&#34;&gt;donate unwanted electronics and computing items&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/continuing-to-downsize/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:58:37 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/continuing-to-downsize/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/continuing-to-downsize.png" type="image/png" length="48470" /> </item> <item> <title>Winding down for 2025</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I have completed my 6,000 km distance goal for cycling, so I will focus on other activities such as walking and yoga. I aim to get into a rhythm of 3 yoga sessions a week, which will stretch my muscles and help with my breathing.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/winding-down-for-2025/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 17:42:49 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/winding-down-for-2025/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/winding-down-for-2025.png" type="image/png" length="48640" /> </item> <item> <title>Something a foot</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>ai-tool-llm</category> <category>clojure</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Completed &lt;a href=&#34;#cycling&#34;&gt;6,000 km distance for cycle riding this year&lt;/a&gt;, a very satisfying number as I wasnt able to do much cycling before May.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A new month means its time to update dependencies across all projects. Although antq has proven very good at reporting outdated dependencies for Clojure projects and GitHub actions, it is quite a niche tool and something extra to learn or maintain a config for.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When reviewing options for liquida/antq there was a link to ... GitHub workflow that generates a PR with all the dependency updates. This project is now in maintenance mode and recommends looking at the Renovate GitHub action.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I decided to create a CI workflow using Renovate that generates a pull request to update Clojure library dependencies and GitHub actions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rather than write this myself, I felt it was a useful task to ask an LLM tool to tackle. I felt confident I knew how to write a clear question (prompt) for the LLM tool. It was also a small enough task that I wouldnt blow all my &#39;free&#39; tokens. I also hoped that it was a simple enough task that I wouldnt have to keep refining the question to get the response I needed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The reply should be simple enough that I can understand, as I already have plenty of experience writing GitHub workflows and configurations for the tools used by a workflow (e.g. Megalinter).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the resulting Renovate.json configuration doesnt like Clojure, so AI seems to have failed quite badly (or was too optimistic).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Taking my usual approach of an Internet search, I discovered the Mend App, which is described in more detail in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.mend.io/integrations/latest/mend-for-github-com&#34;&gt;Mend for GitHub.com docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Mend app kind of works but still seems to require some manual intervention (pressing buttons on developer.mend.io app) and only supports (or only configured for) maven dependencies and not git updates, e.g. seancorfield/deps-new.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The results of the discussion with the LLM are documented in this post and the results were also published to the web:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://claude.ai/public/artifacts/98bc2a13-f609-4bb3-b31e-b5fd47556d85&#34;&gt;Create GitHub workflow with Renovate for Clojure projects&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank .md-button}&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/something-a-foot/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:45:47 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/something-a-foot/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/something-a-foot.png" type="image/png" length="43682" /> </item> <item> <title>Hello darkness my old friend</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;It is getting noticeably darker now, before I finish &#39;working&#39; on Practicalli content and other computer things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the end of last week I &lt;a href=&#34;#clojure-community&#34;&gt;contributed questions to the next Clojure Survey&lt;/a&gt;, which I assume will be out in early January 2026. I also shared some thoughts about why this information was useful to capture.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Earlier this week I ran through the draft survey and provided feedback directly to Christoph. It was mostly nitpicks (I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://conventionalcomments.org/&#34;&gt;:globe_with_meridians: conventional comments style for the feedback&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank}).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Getting close to a total of 6,000 km in distance for 2025. Only 146 km to ride and I&#39;ve hit my target.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;NOTE: the title is taken from the song &#34;Sound of Silence&#34; by &#34;Simon and Garfunkel&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/hello-darkness-my-old-friend/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 19:47:29 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/hello-darkness-my-old-friend/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/hello-darkness-my-old-friend.png" type="image/png" length="49595" /> </item> <item> <title>First taste of Winter</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>git</category> <category>github</category> <category>github-cli</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>ssh-keys</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The days are very cold now, especially when the day is not sunny. I am determined to &lt;a href=&#34;#Cycling&#34;&gt;get out on the bicycle&lt;/a&gt; for several rides each week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Previously I&#39;ve have added SSH keys to my GitHub account via the GitHub website. The GitHub CLI can add SSH keys, which is more convenient that copying the contents of the public SSH key into the website. I still need to figure out a good way to cache an SSH passphrase in a key ring when not using Gnome desktop. I use the SSH key for signing a commit, so need to enter the passphrase for each commit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Friday was house maintenance, replacing the valves for the heating system top-up loop. Now I can top up the water pressure for the heaters when ever needed (which shouldn&#39;t be very often). My neighbors boiler started making a huge banging noise when the pressure was very low, so I can avoid this situation myself (I&#39;ve heard at least one other neibour have the banging boiler problem this week, but couldnt figure out where exactly it came from as its a base sound and travels).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For a distraction this week, I am continuing to watch Blakes 7, Doctor Who (Matt Smith, Jenna Coleman) and Battle of the Planets (possibly the first Americanised Anime).&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/first-taste-of-winter/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 19:24:27 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/first-taste-of-winter/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/first-taste-of-winter.png" type="image/png" length="43123" /> </item> <item> <title>Debian Linux returns</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>debian-linux</category> <category>neovim</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>tui</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Discovered &lt;a href=&#34;#neovim&#34;&gt;Neovim GitSigns plugin&lt;/a&gt; could be used to stage specific lines, as well as hunks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#practicalli&#34;&gt;Material for MkDocs&lt;/a&gt; is the static site generator tool used to create all the Practical.li websites. This project is now in maintenance mode and a project called Zensical is under active development. It seems that there should be a fairly smooth migration of existing projects to the new tool :crossed_fingers:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This summer has been an adventure with the new shiny Hyprland wayland compositor and tiling window manager. Whist Hyprland (and associated tools) can be made very beautiful, I find it has some major productivity limitations compared to i3 tiling window manager.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve switched back my main laptop to using &lt;a href=&#34;#debian-linux&#34;&gt;Debian Linux&lt;/a&gt;, using Sway Wayland Compositor via Regoligh Desktop as Sway works the same way as i3 (at least from a user perspective).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The evaluation of &lt;a href=&#34;#tuis&#34;&gt;Terminal UI tools&lt;/a&gt; is proving much more successful and I have found some nice system tools to use (better than the GUI tools that come with Gnome desktop).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I use the keyboard for everything except graphics &amp;amp; video editing work, and the occasional link in the browser if its a busy page. Using a tiling window manager has helped me keep my fingers on the keyboard where they work the fastest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I common keyboard combination I used is to copy the URL from a browser window into one of the Practicalli books, or this very journal.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Super&lt;/code&gt; and one of h j k l keys to navigate to the browser window (&lt;code&gt;SPC&lt;/code&gt; followed by a number if the browser is on a different desktop)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt; to highlight the current page URL in location bar.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; to copy the URL into the clip board&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Super&lt;/code&gt; and one of h j k l keys to navigate to the Neovim window&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; to paste the URL into the Neovim buffer&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/debian-linux-returns/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 23:27:03 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/debian-linux-returns/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/debian-linux-returns.png" type="image/png" length="42828" /> </item> <item> <title>Another Arch Linux disaster</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>arch-linux</category> <category>clojure</category> <category>debian-linux</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>tui</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;After a &lt;a href=&#34;#arch-linux&#34;&gt;kernel panic with Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; after a package upgrade (and many other issues), I will switch my main machine back to Debian Linux.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I did have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-desktop/issues/1104#issuecomment-3457153534&#34;&gt;small issue starting Regolith on Debian&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} after an update, but there was a fix already defined that was quick to apply successfully.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I can still choose to use Wayland compositor with the Sway tiling window manager, the Wayland equivalent of i3 for Xorg.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tui&#34;&gt;Terminal User Interface tools&lt;/a&gt; are on the rise, so I have started evaluating them to see which ones I want to adopt.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/another-arch-linux-disaster/</link> <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 22:51:48 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/another-arch-linux-disaster/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/another-arch-linux-disaster.png" type="image/png" length="49531" /> </item> <item> <title>Peddle Peddle</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>tui</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of cycling this week with 4 consecutive rides, Thursday to Saturday. The Cafe at East Peckham was closing, so we took a trip as a last farewell. It turns out there is a new buyer, so it should be back open before we know it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I continue to look for the most effective way of &lt;a href=&#34;#cycling&#34;&gt;adding data overlays to the videos captured on cycling routes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Continuing to evaluate &lt;a href=&#34;#tuis&#34;&gt;Terminal UI tools&lt;/a&gt; and finding very useful tools to understand what is going on under the hood of the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/peddle-peddle/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 20:44:29 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/peddle-peddle/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/peddle-peddle.png" type="image/png" length="38222" /> </item> <item> <title>A lighter load</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>hyprland</category> <category>lazyvim</category> <category>neovim</category> <category>omarchy</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Three rides in three consecutive days this week, so I am looking forward to a relaxing Sunday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I continue to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://garudalinux.org/&#34;&gt;Garuda Linux&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;a href=&#34;#hyprland&#34;&gt;Hyprland &amp;amp; Wayland&lt;/a&gt; based system on my main computer and it is an enjoyable experience although there has been quite a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the huge push for &#39;AI&#39; services over the last year has been mostly hype I have dismissed much of it. To evaluate if there is any value in the current &#39;AI&#39; tools I&#39;ve started considering &lt;a href=&#34;#ai-in-reality&#34;&gt;how I gather and organise information&lt;/a&gt;, to find opportunities for optimisation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Downsizing my life continues with my older bicycles and accessories being recycled or upcycled. I am also investigating where are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mynextbike.co.uk/blogs/selling/where-to-sell-your-used-bike&#34;&gt;effective places to sell my bicycle&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank}.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I bought a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sigmasports.com/item/Cannondale/Quick-Carbon-1-Hybrid-Bike-2018/H9PS&#34;&gt;Cannondale Quick Carbon Hybrid bike&lt;/a&gt; back in 2018 for commuting into London (42 minutes was my fastest time into London, this was before the cycle super-highways).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cyclinguk.org/article/how-sell-your-cycle&#34;&gt;Cycling UK&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} has tips on selling a bicycle. There is also a &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.cyclinguk.org/viewforum.php?f=40&amp;amp;sid=726ba7097434b089f0927cf7cf87d0cc&#34;&gt;For Sale Forum&lt;/a&gt;. I have posted my Cannondale hybrid bike on this forum to see if there is interest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bikedelivery.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Bike Delivery&lt;/a&gt; provides a delivery service for 42.99 GBP, with a further 19.99 GBP for a cardboard box to pack the bike in. 100 GBP liability insurance is free, 14.99 GBP for cover up to 500 GBP.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I will still have 3 bicycles left after I sell one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have a much greater appreciation for a simpler life over the last few years (since Covid). I will focus on a small number of things I value deeply.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This simplification lightens my mental load and enables focus on the things I really value. It will also be far easier to relocate, should I find a new place to live.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It sounds like the HMRC is swamped with self-assessment returns. According to the Gov.uk website it will be 44th November by the time they process and reply to my self-assessment submission.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Gov.uk website has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/check-when-you-can-expect-a-reply-from-hmrc&#34;&gt;check the status&lt;/a&gt; where an estimated date will be shown, along with the current submissions date being processed (16th May). It may be worth checking again in a few weeks to see if HMRC has got faster or slower.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/a-lighter-load/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 20:30:32 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/a-lighter-load/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/a-lighter-load.png" type="image/png" length="42370" /> </item> <item> <title>New book on engineering management</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;A meeting I had to discuss engineering teams was postponed, so instead I have started writing &#39;engineering stories&#39; to capture and organise my experiences from various companies and roles. I will capture lessons learned from my experiences (and others) and my current thinking on how to resolve issues that I encountered.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Updated &lt;code&gt;:format/cljfmt-check&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;:format/cljfmt-fix&lt;/code&gt; aliases in &lt;a href=&#34;#clojure&#34;&gt;Practicalli Clojure CLI Config&lt;/a&gt; to use the newer publishing name for the library. The older &lt;code&gt;cljfmt&lt;/code&gt; name did not have a domain, so &lt;code&gt;cljfmt/cljfmt&lt;/code&gt; had to be used as the name when using Clojure CLI. The library published as &lt;code&gt;cljfmt&lt;/code&gt; stopped being updated at versino 0.9.2.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Started a page on &lt;a href=&#34;https://practical.li/engineering-playbook/os/tui/&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-solid-book-open: Terminal User Interface (TUI) apps&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} in the Operating System section of Practicalli Engineering Playbook. I have been using an increasing number of TUI apps, especially after I began using Neovim. I also like apps that are completely keyboard driven, as I am a fast and effective typist and find the mouse very fiddly these days.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/book-template&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-github: GitHub template repository&lt;/a&gt; to quickly create a new Practicalli book or blog web site, using Material for MkDocs. This template repo was used to create &lt;a href=&#34;#practicalli-engineering-manager&#34;&gt;Practicalli Engineering Manger repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Walking, pull-ups and weights are this weeks approach to building up my health again after a few weeks of flu. No cycling since the 8th October, but this had given me a chance to catch up with editing videos of my cycle trips&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/UIunOB88-GI&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-youtube: Isle of Grain&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} 131 km ride to the seaside and back, in 5 hours 45 mins.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/hS-4VSVE5jc&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-youtube: Box Hill via Portuguese Cafe&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} 113 km ride in just over 5 hours, stopping in Limpsfield to photo the wise tutor carving.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/H-euaoMlQnE&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-youtube: South Croydon to Hayes Village Hall&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} 15 minute dash at the end of the Box Hill ride, along the Addington road.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/YNKE1ohasHo&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-youtube: Speedy ride via Speedgate&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} 63 km fast ride in 2 hours 40 minutes.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/new-book-on-engineering-management/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 23:03:47 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/new-book-on-engineering-management/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/new-book-on-engineering-management.png" type="image/png" length="52154" /> </item> <item> <title>A brave new world</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>hyprland</category> <category>lazyvim</category> <category>neovim</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Another 3 cycle rides in a row this week, covering 256 km distance for the week. This would be about 50 km more than I used to commute each week when workin...&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/a-brave-new-world/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 20:12:57 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/a-brave-new-world/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/a-brave-new-world.png" type="image/png" length="43742" /> </item> <item> <title>To the recouperation lounge</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>downsizing</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I remain in recovery mode this week to ensure I am fighting off the current Covid infection completely. I still have sore ears and swollen throat and more tired than normal. I am however getting a lot more sleep and not feeling as ill as previous episodes with covid. I have become very experience with managing this condition.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am applying for engineering manager roles again, a couple of companies a week, mainly through job adverts on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am also posting on LinkedIn on the topic of &#39;AI&#39;, trying to include pragmatic conversations around what the (completely overhyped technology) is actually useful for and what people are currently doing with it. It is interesting that through all the hype around 70% of people using &#39;AI&#39; are not using it for work. Maybe all those recent cat pictures on the internet are fakes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I continue to find &lt;a href=&#34;#downsizing&#34;&gt;things in my life that I can let go of&lt;/a&gt;, making more space in my house and easing a move to a new location when the time is right. I had forgotten how challenging it is to actually deal with cash nowadays, although I was able to deposit almost all of my coins in my bank account.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;NOTE: the title of this post is a reference to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Back_to_Reality_(Red_Dwarf)&#34;&gt;&#34;Back to Reality&#34; episode of Red Dwarf&lt;/a&gt;. Once I am fully recovered, then the next article would be called back to reality 🤣&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;!-- TODO: LinkedIn posts and comments (add links) --&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/to-the-recouperation-lounge/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 22:13:51 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/to-the-recouperation-lounge/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/to-the-recouperation-lounge.png" type="image/png" length="48117" /> </item> <item> <title>Upgrades break often with Arch Linux</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>archlinux</category> <category>hyprland</category> <category>obs</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;OBS screen capture via pipewire has broken again after an &lt;a href=&#34;#arch-linux&#34;&gt;Arch Linux upgrade&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&#39;t see any reports about this issue, but something has changed that broke a working OBS. A rollback of the Btrfs snapshots via the Garuda Linux boot menu restored to a working version.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Editing the video of the &lt;a href=&#34;#cycling&#34;&gt;cycling trip to Grain in August 2025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Its Covid season again and I must scale down my cycling as I have an infection. I did manage a ride on Monday and Wednesday, but on Wednesday evening I had a very bad dizzy spell and uncontrollable shaking for 30 minutes. I couldnt really move and would have called for an ambulance had my phone been in reach. It took a few days to feel okay again, but my energy levels are still feeling compromised.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A break from cycling will be hard as it has significantly helped improve my health. Instead I will rely on walks in the park, at least 1 hour every day (unless its raining all day). I managed a 2 hour walk on Friday to attend a blood test, although was too tired to walk on Saturday. I will endeavour to go for a walk mid-day on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/upgrades-break-often-with-arch-linux/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 21:23:38 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/upgrades-break-often-with-arch-linux/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/upgrades-break-often-with-arch-linux.png" type="image/png" length="56311" /> </item> <item> <title>Darker days</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The days are starting to get shorter. Time to start getting up earlier :)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This year continues to been filled with many dark days across our society of human beings. Selfishness seems abound, driven by fear created by the few to manipulate the many. The ever increasing propaganda seems to know no end.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you are put into a position of constant fear of the other, you are loosing a party of your humanity and missing out in the multitude of joys in our world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is easy to forget that these hostile views are from a vocal minority who really do not understand the damage they are doing to our society and themselves. Unfortunately they also impact the lives of everyone else.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One regular tonne from those in fear is that they are loosing their identity because of others. How can this be the case when each person&#39;s identity is shaped by so many active and passive experiences. Fear shuts down the intricacies of each persons identity. Prolonged fear reduces a person to a mindless savage, capable of unbelievable hate towards others (and themselves).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The movement of people has been the bedrock of human survival and evolution over the last 10,000 years. To think this would ever stop is to deny a significant part of our society. Went people are welcomed into a society, they contribute and become part of a richer society. When we fail to all welcome people into our society then people do not feel they can become a part of our world. When a vocal minority throws hate or even bricks, then not only those on the receiving end feel hurt, our whole society is greatly damaged.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A cold and foggy start to a nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/15975743263&#34;&gt;112 km ride on Monday&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} which brightened up just over half way. I had lots of layers on, including 3 pairs of socks and 3 pairs of gloves. Surprisingly I managed quite a few personal best times along the route. I thought we were going quite steady.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was quite exhausted on Tuesday though, I seem to have some covid or flu symptoms affecting me and draining my energy. I will start doing deliberate breathing to help keep my lungs clear.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wednesday was a big organisation and tidy up of the house, as a plumber is coming to service the boiler on Thursday. I gave away the last of the IKEA 365+ food containers I bought a long time ago. The containers always felt a bit top-heavy (they are tapered with a small base). I posted them on Freegle at the weekend and after one person didnt turn up, another came on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thursday the boiler was serviced and I also arranged a service for my neighbour (who looks after my cats). One of the people I cycle with is a plumber, so its nice to have someone I can trust looking at the boiler. My boiler is in very good condition, which is nice.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Saturday I was helping my neighbour identify the cause of a vibration with their central heating system. After around 45 minutes of heating the radiators, the boiler was creating a very loud vibration. This vibration occurred every 5 minutes or so, for about 30 seconds. I bled the radiators, a couple of which did have a lot of air in. The issue remained. After a bit of a hunt the water pressure&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/darker-days/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 23:39:49 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/darker-days/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/darker-days.png" type="image/png" length="41922" /> </item> <item> <title>Getting healthier Feeling healthier</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>hyprland</category> <category>mkdocs</category> <category>neovim</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve lost 1 and a half bags of sugar in the last 4 days and had an excellent ride through Northern France, so feeling very motivated.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My Hyprland setup is working well, so I should be able to stop yak shaving all the configuration files 🤣 I do need to version control the config and document Garuda Linux and my own preferences for Hyprland.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#neovim&#34;&gt;Neovim 0.11.4&lt;/a&gt; released with a several changes to key bindings to investigate. Some changes are moving to newer standard function calls. There are also new mappings for navigating quicklists, locaiton lists and tag-match lists.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;++&#34;[&#34;++ ++spc++ adds a space above the current line, without moving the cursor&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;++&#34;]&#34;++ ++spc++ adds a space below the current line, without moving the cursor&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/getting-healthier-feeling-healthier/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 23:07:56 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/getting-healthier-feeling-healthier/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/getting-healthier-feeling-healthier.png" type="image/png" length="48673" /> </item> <item> <title>Adventures in Hyprland and France</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>hyprland</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The nights are getting darker but that means more chance for star gazing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#practicalli&#34;&gt;Monthly updates&lt;/a&gt; for practicalli projects, updating dependencies on the Clojure CLI Config and Project Templates repositories.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Testing out &lt;a href=&#34;#cycling&#34;&gt;new toys for the bicycle&lt;/a&gt;, including an electric pump, RideNow TPU inner tubes and Continental Gran Prix 5000 cream &amp;amp; black tyres. Final maintenance before my weekend cycling adventure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;#hyprland&#34;&gt;Hyprland configuration&lt;/a&gt; seems very stable now, with only minor enhancements. I havent quite got a hand of the window layout system yet, at least not in the same way as I could with i3 (Regolith desktop).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Setup Clojure on Arch Linux for the first time. The packaging is well done, although the install location, &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/clojure&lt;/code&gt; is different to the manual script install I am used to on Debian Linux.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/adventures-in-hyprland-and-france/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:28:03 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/adventures-in-hyprland-and-france/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/adventures-in-hyprland-and-france.png" type="image/png" length="50652" /> </item> <item> <title>1001 GitHut Commit Streak</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>ai-tools</category> <category>arch-linux</category> <category>garuda-linux</category> <category>github</category> <category>hyprland</category> <category>movies</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>wellbeing</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 17th August 2025 I completed 1,001 days of successive commits in GitHub (without cheating).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Practicalli Johnny profile - GitHub activity statistics - 1000 day streak&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/graphic-design/blob/live/github/github-profile-practicalli-johnny-1000-streak.png?raw=true&#34;&gt;{loading=lazy}&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some job hunting during the week included being contacted by a recruiter from Docker regarding an engineering manager role (security division). The recruiter that helped get me a position at Citi also got in touch for a healthcare engineering manager role.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Planned a longer cycling route to the Isle of Grain, one of the more remote parts of Kent. Grain village is right by the sea and there is a long sandy beach there. As its a remote location, there are very few people around usually.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve taken several trips to Grain with my friend Gaiville who I trained and cycled with from Lands End to John O&#39;Groats in 2019.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve altered the start of the route previously used to accommodate people from the local cycling club.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Movies to see&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Hail_Mary_(film)&#34;&gt;Project Hail Mary&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Hail_Mary&#34;&gt;Project Hail Mary book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Predator:_Badlands&#34;&gt;Predator: Bad Lands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xeno_(film)&#34;&gt;Xeno&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/watch_the_skies&#34;&gt;Watch The Skies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniela_Forever&#34;&gt;Daniela Forever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Movies watched&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/September_5_(film)&#34;&gt;September 5&lt;/a&gt; covers the terrorist attach at the 1972 Summer Olympics in Munich, told from the perspective of the people working at the ABC sports division who were able to broadcast live much of the tragedy.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Simple_Favor_(film)&#34;&gt;A Simple Favour&lt;/a&gt; with Anna Kendrick in the lead role, as the perfect mom who gets involved with some &#39;interesting&#39; people.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Matrix_(franchise)&#34;&gt;Matrix trilogy&lt;/a&gt; a relaxing bank holiday movie marathon and even after 25 years the movies looks great and are still very engaging.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Current TV shows:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twisted_Metal_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;Twisted Metal&lt;/a&gt; is quirky and fun show with bizarre and disturbing characters who are also quite likeable too.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Trek:_Strange_New_Worlds&#34;&gt;Star Trek Strange New Worlds&lt;/a&gt; I find to be a very fresh and fun take on the Star Trek world, whilst still having darker storylines and background threads.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravity_Falls&#34;&gt;Gravity Falls&lt;/a&gt; watching this show again for about the 5th time, using it as my brain switch on / switch off show. I have watched Rick n Morty too many times :rolling_on_the_floor_laughing:&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/1001-githut-commit-streak/</link> <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:49:19 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/1001-githut-commit-streak/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/1001-githut-commit-streak.png" type="image/png" length="48806" /> </item> <item> <title>Another heatwave</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>creative-tools</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;This week we have the pleasure of another heatwave in the United Kingdom. Its not quite as extreme as the one in July (37 degrees Celsius), but it will in the 30 degree range again for several days.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The week started with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/15422423063&#34;&gt;cycle ride to collect some new shoes&lt;/a&gt;. In training for a ride up a mountain during a French trip I did two more ~100km rides back to back&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/15456165586&#34;&gt;The masochists route ride to Yalding&lt;/a&gt; (ascending some new hills along the way and extra hills on the way back)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/15467902479&#34;&gt;112 Km ride to Box Hill&lt;/a&gt; was surprisingly good, I was more awake than the previous days ride.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/15476759131&#34;&gt;Level 4 ride with Bigfoot CC&lt;/a&gt; was a good recovery ride, only 3 hours long and although hilly (all routes in Kent are) it felt a moderate 738 meters of climbing.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;I use the Lake brand of shoes as they have a wide fit size. Although going through there &lt;a href=&#34;https://uk.lakecycling.com/pages/sizing-chart&#34;&gt;very detailed sizing chart&lt;/a&gt; it was clear that not all shoes were wide enough for my feet (without being far too long).&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/another-heatwave/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 19:22:23 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/another-heatwave/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/another-heatwave.png" type="image/png" length="42930" /> </item> <item> <title>Is AI worth the cost</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;OpenAI gives a curl command to initially test the account setup, then its nothing until a credit card is added to the account. So &lt;a href=&#34;#the-cost-of-ai&#34;&gt;is it actually worth spending money&lt;/a&gt; on something I cannot try out first?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beacon_23&#34;&gt;Beacon 23&lt;/a&gt; again and enjoying it even more a second time around. The first viewing I was a bit confused with the storyline jumps, but it makes a lot more sense now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Editor code assistant plugin for Neovim had a bit update, although it is &lt;a href=&#34;#eca-plugin&#34;&gt;no longer running the ECA server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/is-ai-worth-the-cost/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 19:26:30 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/is-ai-worth-the-cost/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/is-ai-worth-the-cost.png" type="image/png" length="43053" /> </item> <item> <title>The Saga Begins</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>neovim</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I tried using Hyprland with Debian Linux a few months ago but the packages are a little out of date even when using the unstable (SID) distribution. As I had been using SID packages, then the Debian Linux system had become a little too unstable for day to day use. Interestingly I installed the KDE desktop and that worked very nicely before I started again from scratch.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hyperland is kept up to date in Arch Linux although there is a lot more work to learn and maintain arch linux compared to Debian Linux. pacman command options are quite cryptic and I found them hard to memorise. Its also easy to break things doing an update (the downside of a rolling release based distribution).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#garuda-linux&#34;&gt;Garuda Linux&lt;/a&gt; adds some nice tools on top of Arch Linux (and can also used the Nix sub-system) to simplify overall package upgrades and a range of other maintenance tools.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Supporting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/editor-code-assistant/eca-nvim&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-github: editor-code-assistant/eca-nvim&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} project via testing and feedback. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/editor-code-assistant/eca-nvim/pull/2&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-github: Contributed a plugin spec for lazy.nvim plugin manager&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank}. The eca-nvim plugin is in very early stages, but I got a prompt to appear in Neovim :smiley:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Health and fitness continues to improve and the number of cycle rides and distance continues to increase. In July I completed 800km distance from 11 distinct rides, totalling around 35 hours of riding across the month (not including stoppage time).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cycling&#34;&gt;Cycling maintenance&lt;/a&gt; seems to be complete for both the Ribble SL Disc and Bianchi 928 RC road bikes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Aims:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;DONE: &lt;a href=&#34;#cycling&#34;&gt;new cleats&lt;/a&gt; for the black &amp;amp; red Lake shoes (and readjust cleats on white lake shoes)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;DOING: &lt;a href=&#34;#garuda-linux&#34;&gt;upgrade OS on rangerone&lt;/a&gt; (Garuda Linux Hyprland flavor)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;BLOCKED: continue eval of shuttle and rust experiments - on hold due to service outages&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;TODO: update Practicalli Clojure hot loading examples&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/the-saga-begins/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 19:21:55 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/the-saga-begins/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/the-saga-begins.png" type="image/png" length="43736" /> </item> <item> <title>Practicalli working</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>debian-linux</category> <category>neovim</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Much cooler week and my ankle is feeling sore, so more focus on work this week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Aims:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;update Practicalli Clojure hot loading examples&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;continue eval of shuttle and rust experiments - on hold due to service outages&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;new cleats for the black &amp;amp; red Lake shoes&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#garuda-linux&#34;&gt;upgrade OS on rangerone&lt;/a&gt; (Garuda Linux Hyprland flavor)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/practicalli-working/</link> <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:30:25 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/practicalli-working/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/practicalli-working.png" type="image/png" length="43429" /> </item> <item> <title>Practicalli on a minimal budget</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>cycling</category> <category>debian</category> <category>github</category> <category>github</category> <category>journal</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing an article about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/practicalli.github.io/issues/8&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-github: running Practicalli for (almost) zero cost&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank}, only the domain name renewal incurs a yearly fee.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, &lt;a href=&#34;#github&#34;&gt;GitHub started showing a message about a billing problem&lt;/a&gt;. As I shouldn&#39;t be billed for anything I am aware of, further investigation was required. The issue was resolved really quickly by GitHub support, so I can continue with describing how I run Practicalli on a minimal budget.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Movies:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arrival_(film)&#34;&gt;Arrival&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} is a beautiful film with an engaging story, breathtaking cinematography and a very powerful message about the importance of language and communicating. The film opens and closes with the moving &#34;On the Nature of Daylight&#34; composition from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Blue_Notebooks&#34;&gt;The Blue Notebooks&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Richter&#34;&gt;Max Richter&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank}.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cycle rides:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/15132863461&#34;&gt;Speedgate Cafe Wednesday Group&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank .md-button} &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/15157146288&#34;&gt;Bianchi goes to Windsor Castle and back again&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank .md-button}&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/practicalli-on-a-minimal-budget/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 21:18:09 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/practicalli-on-a-minimal-budget/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/practicalli-on-a-minimal-budget.png" type="image/png" length="48838" /> </item> <item> <title>Anniversary of London 7-7</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>bike-maintenance</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>journal</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The week started slow as I was a little tired from the weekend riding. Blender was fired up to edit the videos from the Isle of Wight and Red Barn rides.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Monday was the &lt;a href=&#34;#unexpected-life-as-a-cycle-courier&#34;&gt;20th anniversary of the tragedy of the London bombings&lt;/a&gt; on 7th July 2005. I remember it all too well as I was a cycle courier at at the time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed I finished all the maintenance on my Bianchi 928 RC road bike, which I have had since 2006. The Bianchi is still in excellent condition after a great many journeys and Audax events.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have used a Garmin 1030 cycle computer for the last 7 years and its been really good experience. Unfortunately &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.garmin.com/en-GB/?faq=HX6aQKLbd14PO6JZfEgSv8&amp;amp;productID=567991&amp;amp;searchQuery=mount%20broken&amp;amp;tab=topics&#34;&gt;the mounting tabs have snapped&lt;/a&gt; and can no longer be mounted. I will try and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PxXNjE1efYU&#34;&gt;repair the cycle computer by replacing the back case&lt;/a&gt; and if that fails I will consider trading in for a new Garmin. Either way, it seems time to consider &lt;a href=&#34;#choosing-a-new-cycle-computer&#34;&gt;choosing a new cycle computer for the next 5-10 years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was hit by a large vehicle on the way back from &lt;a href=&#34;#collecting-the-new-cycle-computer&#34;&gt;collecting the new cycle computer&lt;/a&gt;. I was a bit shook up for a day or two but apart from some bruising I seem to be in one piece.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/lKXYYrwTfVU&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-brands-youtube: Bigfoot Club Ride - Hildenborough&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank .md-button}&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/anniversary-of-london-7-7/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 17:46:39 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/anniversary-of-london-7-7/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/anniversary-of-london-7-7.png" type="image/png" length="47239" /> </item> <item> <title>Half way through the year</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>journal</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;It was too hot too think or do anything apart from watch &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twin_Peaks&#34;&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/a&gt; at the start of this week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Updated the versions of libraries used in aliases within &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/clojure-cli-config&#34;&gt;Practicalli Clojure CLI Config&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/clojure-cli-config/releases/tag/2025-07-01&#34;&gt;cut a new release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Watched the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learning.oreilly.com/live-events/practical-rust-with-hands-on-labs/0642572188900/0642572188894/&#34;&gt;OReilly Practical Rust with Hands-On labs live video course&lt;/a&gt; which had &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/andyolsen/rust&#34;&gt;lots of Rust code examples&lt;/a&gt;, including the use of some data science libraries.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Movies and TV this week&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transcendence_(2014_film)&#34;&gt;Transcendence&lt;/a&gt; - an excellent film about a technological singularity and how humans struggle to understand or trust an intelligence that doesn&#39;t look like them. Small minded people end up ruining the world because of something they feared rather than tried to understand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twin_Peaks&#34;&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/a&gt; is a very quirky TV show that was hugely popular when I was in my early 20s. The show has many rich characters and a few very silly ones (depending on your point of view). The storyline is based around a tragic crime that is being investigated by Agent Dale Cooper. Agent Cooper is not your typical FBI agent and really makes the show worth watching all by themselves 😃&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/half-way-through-the-year/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:21:55 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/half-way-through-the-year/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/half-way-through-the-year.png" type="image/png" length="47989" /> </item> <item> <title>Clojure LSP, Rust, Cycling &amp; Bike maintenance</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>clojure</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>journal</category> <category>rust</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;#clojure-lsp&#34;&gt;Neovim section on the Clojure LSP site&lt;/a&gt; needed an update, so I created a PR with more information and updated configuration links.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cycling&#34;&gt;Bicycle maintenance and a few final ride&lt;/a&gt; this week in preparation for the ride around the Isle of Wight. There were more replacements than I first thought, brake pads, cleats, pedals. I have done lots of long distance riding for most of the last 6 years (except the COVID years) so I shouldn&#39;t have been surprised.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have been looking at more products from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliexpress.com/&#34;&gt;AliExpress&lt;/a&gt; and revisited the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_bdB2qt0Tp8&#34;&gt;Trace Velo video about Ali Express and if its worth it&lt;/a&gt; for tips on getting the most out of this website. If you know exactly what you are looking for and buy from established companies, then it is as good as using services like Amazon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pandapodium.cc/&#34;&gt;Panda Podium&lt;/a&gt; is a company that makes it easy to find quality products from China based manufactures, greatly reducing the risk. They also have some good reviews of products too.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Investigating the Rust language again this week, in between the cycle training, maintenance and heatwave 🤣 There is a great looking deployment platform called Shuttle for Rust apps, feels like the same enjoyable experience as Heroku.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tv &amp;amp; Movies this week:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Blade Runner: The Final Cut - one of my favourite films of all time, I never get tired of watching.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(2024_film)&#34;&gt;Flow&lt;/a&gt; a wonderful movie (especially if you love cats, which I do). Animation and music were very moving.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/clojure-lsp-rust-cycling--bike-maintenance/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 19:06:43 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/clojure-lsp-rust-cycling--bike-maintenance/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/clojure-lsp-rust-cycling--bike-maintenance.png" type="image/png" length="63579" /> </item> <item> <title>Getting hot</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>artificial-intelligence</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>github</category> <category>music</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Kingdom is heading for another heatwave.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Continuing to train for a cycling trip at the end of the month. Lots of Yoga and a long ride at the weekend. Finding &lt;a href=&#34;#cycling&#34;&gt;some interesting routes for training&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;GitHub sent an email about &lt;a href=&#34;#github-org&#34;&gt;charging the Practicalli Org&lt;/a&gt;. Investigation revealed a change in that GitHub started to meter usage of user accounts and Organisations since March/April 2025.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am starting to collect my thoughts about AI (and dig up information about software agents I researched back in 1997). An interesting aspect of AI is &lt;a href=&#34;#misconception-of-ai&#34;&gt;the relationship that people are building with AI&lt;/a&gt;, both positive and in some cases a little disturbing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Welcome_to_the_Pleasuredome&#34;&gt;&#34;Welcome to the Pleasuredome&#34; by Frankie Goes To Hollywood&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank}, specifically the anti-war song &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Two_Tribes&#34;&gt;Two Tribes&lt;/a&gt;, reminded me of the early 1980&#39;s and the deep concern about nuclear war, which seems to be an increasing risk at the present time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The toppling of US-aligned governments in Iran and Nicaragua and the Soviet-Afghan war drove a significant increase of tension in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold_War&#34;&gt;cold war&lt;/a&gt;, as make prevalent in the UK by the government&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Protect_and_Survive&#34;&gt;protect and survive&lt;/a&gt; public information campaign.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I remember watching the file &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Threads_(1984_film)&#34;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt;, an apocalyptic nuclear war drama which they actually showed us as school. The family in the film was very similar to my own when they were younger, so it did have a significant impact. After watching the film I realised how ineffectually the protect and survive information was.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The current near term risk to nuclear war being the violence over the continued land grab in the middle east, driven and masked by fear and hatred that has been there longer than everyone currently alive today. All this propped up with certain people using the politics of popularism to their own financial advantage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The longer term risk of nuclear war of course being countries fighting over ever dwindling resources, e.g. food and clean water &amp;amp; air, due to disastrous changes to the climate of planet Earth driven by unsustainable human activities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The 1980&#39;s had many songs that covered the darker part of humanity, often in a subtle way that people listening to the songs didn&#39;t realise (or want to realise). Here are a few examples I remembered:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luka_(song)&#34;&gt;Luka by Suzanne Vega&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} was quite a harrowing picture of child abuse and how&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Every_Breath_You_Take&#34;&gt;Every breath you take by The Police&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} which is often though of as a love song and was in part about stalking and part authoritarian &#39;Big Brother&#39; control of the people&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russians_(song)&#34;&gt;Russians by Sting&lt;/a&gt; was a commentary on the dangers of the &#39;Mutually Assured Destruction&#39; doctrine pushed by the governments of the USA and Soviet Union. The song also inspired in part the nuclear war story of the Terminator movies.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everybody_Wants_to_Rule_the_World&#34;&gt;Everybody wants to run the world&lt;/a&gt; decries peoples desire for control and power, often at the expense of others. The song originally titled &#39;Everybody wants to go to war&#39; so reflecting aspects of the cold-war. The song also hints at humanities lack of respect for the environment.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_the_Air_Tonight&#34;&gt;In The Air Tonight by Phil Collins&lt;/a&gt; venting the frustration, anger and despair that so often accompanies divorce. A very poignant song personally as my parents had a very tumultuous divorce at that time that greatly affected me for many years.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/getting-hot/</link> <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 01:37:51 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/getting-hot/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/getting-hot.png" type="image/png" length="40845" /> </item> <item> <title>johnny turbo</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>ai</category> <category>clojure</category> <category>cycle-maintenance</category> <category>cycling</category> <category>debian-linux</category> <category>practicalli</category> <category>rust</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Started the week with a much stronger ride than I have been able to do this year. I had the energy and motivation to push myself, especially on ascents.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally finished backing up the Lenovo Extreme laptop. Tried out &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Garuda Linux Hyprland version&lt;/a&gt; which was nicely organised with lots of neat desktop tools.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#debian-linux&#34;&gt;Installed Debian Linux&lt;/a&gt; as Garuda Linux had issues installing on the Software RAID partitions that the laptop had (two 512 GB drives in RAID 0). I recreated the Software RAID with the Debian installer anyway, so maybe Garuda Linux would install on the recreated array. I am not ready to switch to Wayland yet as there are a few key applications that are not yet supported.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/johnny-turbo/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 19:20:29 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/johnny-turbo/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/johnny-turbo.png" type="image/png" length="40118" /> </item> <item> <title>Passwords Fixes Maintenance and Tools</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>debian-linux</category> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I had an interview for a new role last week and it seems a very interesting company. The seem very organised and clear in their communication and I am on to the next step :smiley_cat:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Putting the finishing touches to the &lt;a href=&#34;#debian-linux&#34;&gt;Debian Linux install on the Lenovo Extreme laptop&lt;/a&gt;. Reviewed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://deb.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Debian Linux mirrors&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} work as its been a while. &lt;code&gt;deb.debian.org&lt;/code&gt; contains the SRV records in DNS that manages the routing to the most appropriate package archive, so I dont need to do anything to have the best mirror.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I found a &lt;a href=&#34;#configure-dark-theme-in-gtk4-apps&#34;&gt;solution to GTK4 apps not using the dark theme&lt;/a&gt; in i3 (Regoligth), so the world is a happy place again :face_with_rolling_eyes:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Testing out 1Password password manager as a replacement for NordPass which was used for the last couple of years. :crossed_fingers:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Update: 1Password is so much nicer experience getting setup so I will definitely switch. An interesting thing I saw when signing up for an account was that 1Password first did a credit card check by trying to take 1 USD from my account. As the account was empty then my bank refused the withdrawal. So 1Password asked for $0 dollars instead, which my bank app prompted me to accept. I have 7 days trial to change my mind before they take the annual payment (32 Euros).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Started the &lt;a href=&#34;https://practical.li/rust&#34;&gt;Practicalli Rust book&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank} although this is only the structure of the book and the CI publishing workflow for the moment. It does provide a central place to capture all my experiences with Rust and hopefully it will become useful to others in the near future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;TV &amp;amp; Movies this week:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Evil Dead III - Army of Darkness: my favorite movie of the series, I&#39;ve watched this dozens of times and always enjoy.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Paradise - an interesting show with good characters&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Rich and Morty season 8 on Channel 4: first two episodes have been very enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/passwords-fixes-maintenance-and-tools/</link> <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 23:21:32 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/passwords-fixes-maintenance-and-tools/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/passwords-fixes-maintenance-and-tools.png" type="image/png" length="56043" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 88 - Clojure driven finance startup and 4Clojure</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Another &lt;a href=&#34;#4clojure-challenges&#34;&gt;4Clojure challenge&lt;/a&gt;, this time #9 covering sets in Clojure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A lunch with a another company with Clojure roles, cycling to and from the meeting on the Bromptom.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Weirdest Interview&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The company is called Be-Social, a finance startup that is building an app to make spending money a more social activity and enabling friends and colleagues to share bills and other expenses.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The interview with the Founder and CTO when very well and the role was very clear to me. Unfortunately the follow-on interview with two developers when very poorly as they seemed to be interviewing me for a very different role.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The developers didn&#39;t seem at all prepared and were &#39;trying something different&#39; apparently.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We started with what they called a &#39;pairing session&#39; where they handed my a laptop (it was a Mac and I had not used one in a long time). I struggled to use the mouse to click and the developers couldn&#39;t (be bothered to) explain how they had set it up. I muddled on...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &#39;pairing&#39; continued where I struggled to use the Mac and IntelliJ (something else I hadn&#39;t used) to try understand a code base using libraries I had never used. I asked questions about the code but the developers refused to answer them, saying I should just experiment with the code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I couldn&#39;t figure out how the Clojure REPL worked in IntelliJ and they didn&#39;t know either, my ability to experiment was severely limited. It wasn&#39;t even clear how to start the application so I could see it running or run any unit tests. The developers just stat there and watched the screen or stared at me, without answering any questions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;By this time I was becoming quite disillusioned with the developers in front of me. I was trying not to focus on the question of why I wanted to work with people so closed as this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that neither of the developers interviewing me were playing their part in the &#39;pairing&#39; process and watched me struggle instead. Actually one of the developers was feeling so out of their depth that they didn&#39;t really engage in any part of the interview, except to say that they were feeling out of their depth when I did ask about their role during our brief introductions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After 30 minutes of not &#39;pairing&#39; with me, they proceeded to quiz me on obscure information about REST. One of the developers took great pride in how much they had learned about REST, the four levels of REST and lots of other niche information. This seemed to be the measure of how good an engineer would be, mainly because that is how his previous (and only) tech lead had worked.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I walked out of the interview at the end with the final words that they should talk to their founder about what they are looking for, to save everyone some time. I had no illusions that any kind of follow-up from the interview would be forth-coming. I was pleased not to have to even consider a role there.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Its not the first time (probably no the last) that people within a company have wildly different expectations. Its like they haven&#39;t actually talked to each other about the role :shocked_face_with_exploding_head:&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-88---clojure-driven-finance-startup-and-4clojure/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-88---clojure-driven-finance-startup-and-4clojure/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-88---clojure-driven-finance-startup-and-4clojure.png" type="image/png" length="65144" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 90 - What will be my next role</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>4clojure</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Considering my options for my next role. There have been a lot of really interesting roles I have interviewed for. There is one that seems to require the widest use of my skills.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;4Clojure Challenge #11 - conj with maps&#34;&gt;https://github.com/practicalli/four-clojure/blob/master/src/four_clojure/011-maps-conj.clj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-90---what-will-be-my-next-role/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-90---what-will-be-my-next-role/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-90---what-will-be-my-next-role.png" type="image/png" length="53726" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 91 - Chasing references and 4Clojure</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Chasing references for my next potential employers&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Quick write up about 4Clojure exercise #16 - Hello world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;4Clojure challenge #16 Hello World&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/639cf76e7901809413eb01f9c5a2f07187764ae0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-91---chasing-references-and-4clojure/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-91---chasing-references-and-4clojure/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-91---chasing-references-and-4clojure.png" type="image/png" length="60054" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 92 - Clojure Hack day</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Clojure Hack day was quite a small event however it gave us a chance to work on our own projects. Worked with Mani on some basic Clojure skills. Als worked on building a simple ClojureScript React style website with our primary school student (accompanied by her mom)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I also did a little more work with Scalable Vector Graphics, in the system monitor project I started a while ago.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;SkillsMatter were kind enough to invite us to join in the event, however, there was some issue with food and SkillsMatter did initially exclude the Clojure group although eventually we were included in the event again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;CIDER logo in Clojure SVG syntax&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jr0cket/webapp-status-monitor/commit/ce60f78c35ce737333c9b9b24b83caca6b49b596&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-92---clojure-hack-day/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-92---clojure-hack-day/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-92---clojure-hack-day.png" type="image/png" length="51791" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 93 - Clojure Study group - ClojureScript reagent website with SVG</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Extremely tired today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Code from today&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;Simple ClojureScript front end website with reagent&#34;&gt;https://github.com/practicalli/example-clojurescript-reagent-svg-website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-93---clojure-study-group---clojurescript-reagent-website-with-svg/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-93---clojure-study-group---clojurescript-reagent-website-with-svg/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-93---clojure-study-group---clojurescript-reagent-website-with-svg.png" type="image/png" length="66795" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 94 - Coaching and Emacs talk at Linux in London</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>4clojure</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Cycled into London today on the Brompton and my Tannus tyres still going strong. I finally got a moment to clean them too.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another very productive coaching day in Wagamama today, covering the inside out approach to writing Clojure. I pushed 3 out of the 6 exercise we completed to Github.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cycled over to SkillsMatter to give (finish writing) my Emacs for your digital life talk for Linux in London community.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Code from today&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/82f284d3760eb2c329888c15a2f377dc28db454e&#34;&gt;4Clojure #46&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/997d76e4b2487369add9e492070265aa857294f1&#34;&gt;4Clojure #47&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/4b305199b4d3b1770388f4fa037542b426176c80&#34;&gt;4Clojure #48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-94---coaching-and-emacs-talk-at-linux-in-london/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-94---coaching-and-emacs-talk-at-linux-in-london/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-94---coaching-and-emacs-talk-at-linux-in-london.png" type="image/png" length="60386" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 95 - AI startup team lunch - 4Clojure exercises</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>4clojure</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Team lunch with the team I will be working with in the new year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The venue was a very basic restaurant but with nice food. There are some interesting dynamics in the team, so will need to figure out how to work with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-95---ai-startup-team-lunch---4clojure-exercises/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-95---ai-startup-team-lunch---4clojure-exercises/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-95---ai-startup-team-lunch---4clojure-exercises.png" type="image/png" length="63632" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 96 - User Feedback session &amp; 4Clojure exercises</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>4clojure</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;User feedback session for an interesting AI product client that I will be involved with in the new year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sometimes listening is a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-96---user-feedback-session--4clojure-exercises/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-96---user-feedback-session--4clojure-exercises/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-96---user-feedback-session--4clojure-exercises.png" type="image/png" length="69006" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 97 Planning 2019 and 4Clojure</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>4clojure</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Planning activities for 2019, including ClojureBridge London events.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/four-clojure/commit/003fcabec954eed8005feff989136681a36b7026&#34;&gt;4Clojure exercise #51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-97-planning-2019-and-4clojure/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-97-planning-2019-and-4clojure/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-97-planning-2019-and-4clojure.png" type="image/png" length="57006" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 98: Coaching and 4Clojure 53</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>4clojure</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Continued coaching one of my regular students&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Took Poppy (one of my cats) to the vets for a checkup. Apart from a some plaque build Poppy is fine. More toothpaste and teeth cleaning for Poppy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cycled into Wagamama Southbank for another coaching session, getting my teeth stuck into 4Clojure challenge #53, a tricky one eventually solved with &lt;code&gt;partition&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;partition-by&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;!!! INFO &#34;4Clojure solution&#34; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/four-clojure/commit/846c62fa2b95a844368d72011f0cc1d361bb4470&#34;&gt;4Clojure #53 solution&lt;/a&gt;{target=_blank}&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-98-coaching-and-4clojure-53/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-98-coaching-and-4clojure-53/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-98-coaching-and-4clojure-53.png" type="image/png" length="60558" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 100: 4Clojure</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>4clojure</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Walked through 4Clojure challenges number 16 to 22 in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/8u8y73zh0w0&#34;&gt;Clojure virtual study group broadcast today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-100-4clojure/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-100-4clojure/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-100-4clojure.png" type="image/png" length="45684" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 100: 4Clojure</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>4clojure</category> <category>clojure</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;100 days of code challenge completed. Was it worth it? Well yes, it got me coding almost every day, and overall I certainly achieved more than 100 hours of coding, more like several 100 hours of coding.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I didnt do was work on a specific project every day, but that would have felt more like work and I enjoyed having a break from that routine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Will I do a 100 days of code challenge again? Not sure, its quite a hard thing to be consistent with. I will certainly keep a developer journal from now on as it has been very useful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;!!! INFO &#34;4Clojure solution&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Write up of the 4Clojure exercises I covered in yesterdays Clojure study group broadcast. Popped out for a few essentials in the last day I am prepared to go shopping before the holidays :) - [4Clojure #17](https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/7ff29a9f7014fde30e133f88f78c15d8729ed68e){target=_blank} - [4Clojure #18](https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/f75d84c2ab82b0b74c6b87b29935c2a4e175cfc0){target=_blank} - [4Clojure #19](https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/0a4a8561b951284aa90910f339cdae9c20225007){target=_blank} - [4Clojure #20](https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/91616e84ed16803a76734a443a7a4b3b65c20262){target=_blank} - [4Clojure #21](https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/5fe42949b7123c42a6b8d1f6ab8df2c7afc8f200){target=_blank} - [4Clojure #22](https://github.com/jr0cket/four-clojure/commit/d7444b2f3f2f39937c4889cb080724ac790ec374){target=_blank} &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-100-4clojure/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-100-4clojure/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-100-4clojure.png" type="image/png" length="45684" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 101: An extra day of code</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>clojure</category> <category>games</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Added more 4Clojure solutions&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;def&lt;/code&gt; supports a doc-string (I missed that ability previously).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Emacs Window management when running tests in Cider with Spacemacs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Logitech MX Ergo trackball mouse arrived today and it is so nice to use. Its a trackball so the mouse itself stays static on the desk avoiding the need to move my hand around and therefore reducing RSI. Using a trackball also means very little space is use. The trackball is tilted so the hand is in a natural and more comfortable position, the same position I configured with my tented Model01 keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-101-an-extra-day-of-code/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-101-an-extra-day-of-code/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-101-an-extra-day-of-code.png" type="image/png" length="53117" /> </item> <item> <title>Day 106: TicTacToe for Virtual Study Group</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>100daysofcode</category> <category>clojure</category> <category>games</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Walking through &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/_eO7EsXO2XE&#34;&gt;a video taking a functional approach to the Tic-Tac-Toe game&lt;/a&gt; for the Clojure study group.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Code from today&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/tictactoe-cli/commit/7340a474e1c7d25a65f22383b6a3848ed055b0bd&#34;&gt;Uppercase player names&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/tictactoe-cli/commit/cef31c50181b6e7af16e586f9946b10672dc6f9d&#34;&gt;Display board with a grid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/practicalli/tictactoe-cli/commit/c0ed5b42124540b0ad2d6dc21fa54e6127237dd6&#34;&gt;Refactor play-game to pure function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/day-106-tictactoe-for-virtual-study-group/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/day-106-tictactoe-for-virtual-study-group/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/day-106-tictactoe-for-virtual-study-group.png" type="image/png" length="60784" /> </item> <item> <title>Monthly library updates</title> <author>Practicalli Johnny</author> <category>practicalli</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;The last monthly review of library dependency versions in Clojure CLI Config aliases for 2023&lt;/p&gt;</description> <link>https://practical.li/journal/monthly-library-updates/</link> <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate> <source url="https://practical.li/journal/feed_rss_updated.xml">Practicalli Personal Journal</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://practical.li/journal/monthly-library-updates/</guid> <enclosure url="https://practical.li/journal/assets/images/social/monthly-library-updates.png" type="image/png" length="49217" /> </item> </channel> </rss>